A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Memorabilia FA1077
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Memorabilia
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University.
FA1077
7.2 Cubic Feet
2 boxes, 2 packages and additional individual items. Size of box 2: 4 x 4 x 12 Size of package: 18 x 22 x 2 1/2.
Conditions Governing Access note
Collection is open for research will select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
All inquiries to view memorabilia require advanced notice of at least 48 business hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Box 2: Received from the office of the Business Manager, 1980 April. Package 1: Received from the office of the Business Manager, 1977 May.
Scope and Contents
Over the years since the founding of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (RIMR) various ephemera, citations of appreciation, medals of commemoration, documents of greeting, and other forms of recognition have been received. A varied assortment has been assembled and arranged together.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 1000
- Celebration program of City College of the City of New York, 1912 November 16 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Held for a two-fold purpose: Greetings to Alexis Carrel on winning Nobel Prize (including response by Carrel; To unveil model of proposed stadium by Arnold Brunner (Gift of Adolph Lewisohn.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Due to the nature and potentially brittle condition of this material, special arrangements may be required in order to view materials. Individual items may be restricted due to preservation concerns.
- Photographic copy of letter from Theobald Smith to Dr. Krumbhaar on the cummulative nature of scientific discoveries, 1933 October 11 (Box 1)
- Certification by the Board of Regents of the American College of Physicians of RIH (Box 1)
- Greetings at Convocation, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Document of greeting from Bologna University. Also gold medal., 1959; On vellum in leather folder with leather slip case; medal in leather box. (Box 1)
  - Document of greeting from Harvard University, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Document of greeting from Cambridge University, 1959; Vellum in leather covered box with proofs on paper. (Box 1)
  - Document of greeting from Oxford University, 1959; Vellum in cardboard tube. (Box 1)
  - Medal from University of Lima, Gold in leather box with decal. (Box 1)
- Convocation, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Vellum proof of RI LLD degree presented to Thomas Sherrer Boarse, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Vellum proof of RI ScD degree presented to Peyton Rous, 1959 (Box 1)
- Princeton University Bicentennial Medal on stand, 1746/1946 (Box 1)
  Biographical / Historical
  Sent to New York City when Department of Animal and Plant Pathology consolidated with New York City Laboratories.
- Engraving plates for RIMR bookplate (Box 1)
  - 1 of seal; 1 of seal with name. (Box 1)
  - Name for use with Institute seal (Box 1)
  - "Gift of Theobald Smith", 1915 (Box 1)
  - "Mary Harris Gayley Memorial", 1918 (Box 1)
- Middlesex County Board of Agriculture "Corn Trophy": Silver loving cup for best exhibitor of 4th class. George H. Roeder, Clyde, NJ, 1913 November 27 (Box 1)
- Award of Distinction to RIMR, presented by American Pharmaceutical Manufacturer's Association, New York City, 1945 December 10 (Box 1)
  In recognition of its great contribution to public health by fundamental research in the field of medical science which is of profound and lasting value to mankind.
- Brussels International Expedition: Citation of thanks from U.S. Department of State in recognition of the Institute's Public Service., 1958 (Box 1)
- Ola from Ceylon: Gift of palm leaf manuscript of sinolese medicine., 1928 (Box 1)
- Oil painting, 2 on canvas in rolls. (Box 1)
- Medal from University of Paris, 1920 (Box 1)
  Reported in Minutes of 1920 January 17 in Commemoration of the Institute's service to science during WWI.
- David painting of Lavorisier (Box 1)
  - Color photograph; impression of Lavoisier medal presented to RIMR by Mr. Eidlitz, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Framed early print of Lavoisier laboratory (Box 1)
- Etching: Presented to the Theobald Smith House by Dr. J.M. Rasek, Brno, Czechoslovakia, 1922 (Box 1)
  Etching is a Czech scene.
- Certificate of Achievement to Rockefeller Institute Hospital, presented by the Bureau of Medicine and Surgery of the U.S. Navy (Box 1)
  "In grateful acknowledgement of exceptional cooperation and outstanding services rendered ot the Medical Department of the Navy during the period of WWII".
- Clippings, 1901-1924; 1; microfilm reel. (Box 2)
  Rockefeller's gift to Nogucni, Esp. 1928 May 29.
- Scrapbook, 1925-1941; 2; microfilm reel. (Box 2)
  up to p. 240.
- Bronze medals of Lavoisier, 5 (Box 2)
- "Rub" of medal of Lavoisier, Presented to the RIMR by Richard Eidlitz., 1 (Box 2)
- Medal of Theobald Smith: "Boston 1915", 1 (Box 2)
- Paul Ehrlich medal, 1904 March 14; 1 (Box 2)
- Centennial Medal, Royal Society of Medical and Natural Sciences, Brussels, 1822/1922 (Box 2)
  Custodial History
  bears note dated 1940 February 15 -- "can find no record of source".
- Commemorative Medal Louisiana Purchase Exposition, 1904 (Box 2)
- Harvard Tricentennial Medal, 1636/1936 (Box 2)
- Rockefeller Institute I.D. pins, 1911, 1917 (Box 2)
- Architect's rendering of proposed Hospital addition., Mounted for presentation to Boards and Committees. (Box 3)
  This design was not adopted.
- "Diplome of Grand Prix avec felicitations du Jry" from the Exposition" (Box 3)
- Etching presented to RIMR from the French Educational Mission, 1918-1919 (Box 3)
- Louis Schmidt etchings, 1968 July (Box 3)
  11 pieces in the master set pulled from the original plates, 1968 July. Some prints were made and the plates were then destroyed. In this set there are an additional 4 prints collected from various places.
- Aerial views of the Princeton laboratories, 2 (Box 3)
  Photograph by McLaughlin Aerial Survey
- Building plans, 1970s; Package (Box 4)
  In the 1970s, a suggestion was made to acquire air rights over the East River Drive for the purpose of some building expansion to be developed jointly with the neighboring medical institutions. The air rights were finally granted but final decisions to utilize them were abandoned.
  However at one point consulting engineers and landscape architects, Clarke adn Rapuano presented plans for utilizing present land areas for additional buildings. The drawings were mounted and presented for consideration to the Board of Trustees.